Rohail Mustafa Syed

Email: rmsyed@umich.edu, Phone: (734)-474-5198 Website: http://www-personal.umich.edu/~rmsyed/

OBJECTIVES

To advance the cause of learning and expand the realm of knowledge through research and collaboration with visionaries and thought leaders as part of a world class team. Carry out projects and studies which contribute towards understanding, investigating, designing and developing of viable solutions to interesting and challenging questions. To create market and social value through innovation and entrepreneurship!

EDUCATION

•	PhD Information (In-Progress) CGPA: 3.787/4.00	2014-Present
	School of Information	
	University of Michigan, Ann Arbor	
•	BSc Engineering	2010-2014
	School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (SEECS),	
	National University of Sciences and Technology (NUST), Islamabad	

WORKSHOPS & ONLINE COURSES

•	Conducted IEEE Flash Workshop for Engineering Students at NUST	2011
•	Participant IEEE Android Development Workshop	2011
•	Machine Learning Online Course, Stanford University, USA	2011
•	Introduction to Databases Online Course, Stanford University, USA	2011

WORK EXPERIENCE & ASSISTANTSHIP

•	Graduate Student Research Assistant (GSRA) at University of Michigan	2014-Present
•	Teaching Assistant (TA) for course of Engineering Economics at NUST	2012
•	Summer Internship on Android Budget Management Project at NUST	2012
•	Paid Research Internship – Android Based Home Automation	2012
	Project sponsored by National Radio and Telecom Corporation (NRTC)	
•	Research Internship – iTeach,uLearn innovative Teaching, universal Learning Project	2013
	Project sponsored by National Foundation for Resource Development (NFRD)	

RESEARCH/SEMESTER PROJECTS

•	Optimizing Search Ranking for Educational Goals	2015-Present
•	Real-time Intrinsically Diverse Search engine	2014-2015
•	Autonomous Landmine Detection and Mapping System	2014
•	Accelerometer-based Virtual Archery	2013
•	Android Home Automation System	2012
•	Online Crime Reporting System	2012
•	Fast Food Order and Delivery System	2007

RESEARCH PAPERS

•	Syed, R. and Collins-Thompson, K. Optimizing Search Results for Educational Goals:	2016
	Incorporating Keyword Density as a Retrieval Objective.	
•	Collins-Thompson, K., Rieh, S. Y., Haynes, C. C., and Syed, R. Assessing learning outcomes in web search: A comparison of tasks and query strategies. In <i>Proceedings of the 2016 ACM on Conference on Human Information Interaction and Retrieval</i> (2016), ACM, pp. 163-172.	2016

COMPUTER SKILLS

- **General Purpose Programming** C, C++, Java, Python, Visual Basic 6.0
- **Data Processing Programming** R, Matlab, Octave
- Web Development (Client-side)

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Flash

• Web Development (Server-side)

PHP, MySQL, SQLite

• Mobile Development

Android

• Hardware Development

Assembly Code, Embedded C, Raspberry Pi

ACHIEVEMENTS

•	President's Gold Medal for Academics at NUST	2014
•	Won 3 rd place award for best Final Year Project	2014
•	Academic Merit Scholarship	2010-2014
•	Stanford Extended Education Program Advanced 2011 Track Courses	2011
•	IEEE-SEECS Chapter Webmaster at NUST	2011
•	IEEE-SEECS Chapter Member Executive Committee at NUST	2012
	Certified IBM DB2 Academic Associate	2012
•	Chief Minister Academic Achievement Award	2013

PROFESSIONAL INTERESTS

- Information Retrieval
- Human-Computer Interaction
- Artificial Intelligence, Data Mining & Pattern Recognition